Guide to the Doris Duke Foundation records, 1934-2009 (bulk 1948-1982)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1934-2009
  - Denied Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1976–1977 (2 of 2) (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Possible Donations: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemption, April 1977–May 1977 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - American Indians and Friends – Bob Burnett: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes photographs and 1977 tax exemptions, 1977–1982 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Possible Donations: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions, 1977 May (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Donations 1977: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1977 June (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Save the Whales Hawaii – Greenpeace Foundation, Lou Pursel: Miscellaneous Donations Files. Includes clippings and 1977 tax exemptions, 1977 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Morristown Memorial Hospital, 1977 Jul–Nov (1 of 2) (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Morristown Memorial Hospital, 1977 Jul–Nov (2 of 2) (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Girls and Boys Service League: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1977 Sep (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Church of Light – Reverend Fred Houston: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1977–1978 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Hillsborough Boys’ Football Association: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1977 Nov (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Submitted January 24, 1978. Denials sent March 17, 1978, 1977–1978 (1 of 2) (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Submitted January 24, 1978. Denials sent March 17, 1978, 1977–1978 (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donations Files, 1977 Dec–1978 Apr (1 of 3) (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donations Files, 1977 Dec–1978 Apr (2 of 3) (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donations Files, 1977 Dec–1978 Apr (3 of 3) (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Donations 1978: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1977–1978 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Submitted March 31, 1978, 1978 Jan–Mar (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Tune In, Inc. – Jane Pickens Hoving: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1978–1981 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Submitted April 13, 1978, 1978 Mar–Apr (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings. Submitted June 1978, 1978 Apr–Jun (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings. Submitted June 1978, 1978 Apr–Jun (2 of 2) (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Deborah Hospital Foundation (N.J.), 1978 May–Jul (1 of 3) (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Deborah Hospital Foundation (N.J.), 1978 May–Jul (2 of 3) (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Deborah Hospital Foundation (N.J.), 1978 May–Jul (3 of 3) (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings. Submitted August 28, 1978, 1978 Jul–Aug (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clipping and tax exemptions. Contains Somerset County Community Health Center and N.J. Society for the Prevention of Blindness. Submitted October 27, 1978, 1978 Aug–Oct (1 of 2) (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous donation files. Includes appeals renewed, 1974-1978 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation form letters, 1976 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Doris Duke Foundation general correspondence and donations, 1970-1979, 1977 and undated (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Letters of appreciation - Doris Duke Foundation, 1978-1979 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clipping and tax exemptions. Contains Somerset County Community Health Center and N.J. Society for the Prevention of Blindness. Submitted October 27, 1978, 1978 Aug–Oct (2 of 2) (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - New York Foundling Hospital – Center for Parent and Child Development: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1978 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Verbal Interaction Project – Mother-Child Home Program: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes 1958 tax exemption, 1978 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Corporation for Children and Families – Cranbury, N.J.: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes 1978 tax exemption, 1978 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clipping and tax exemptions. Contains the Center for Women in Crisis (Maplewood, N.J.) and Newark Preservation and Landmarks Committee. Submitted March 30, 1979, 1979 Jan–Mar (1 of 2) (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clipping and tax exemptions. Contains the Center for Women in Crisis (Maplewood, N.J.) and Newark Preservation and Landmarks Committee. Submitted March 30, 1979, 1979 Jan–Mar (2 of 2) (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Y.W.C.A. of Trenton, N.J., 1979 Apr–Jul (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions. Contains North Essex Development and Action Council and Somerset County College. Submitted September 29, 1979, 1979 Aug–Sep (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Donations 1979: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1979–1980 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1979 Oct–1980 Jan (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions. Contains Clara Maass Memorial Hospital (Belleville, N.J.), Muhlenberg Hospital (Plainfield, N.J.), and Mulberry Street Child Care & Community Center (Trenton, N.J.). Submitted May 1980, 1979 Jul–1980 May (1 of 2) (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions. Contains Clara Maass Memorial Hospital (Belleville, N.J.), Muhlenberg Hospital (Plainfield, N.J.), and Mulberry Street Child Care & Community Center (Trenton, N.J.). Submitted May 1980, 1979 Jul–1980 May (2 of 2) (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions. Contains Transportation for Independent Living (Orange, N.J.), 1979 Dec–1980 May (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey and New York Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions, 1980 May–Aug (1 of 2) (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - New Jersey and New York Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions, 1980 May–Aug (2 of 2) (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Donations 1980: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1980 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings, 1980 Oct–Dec (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions. Contains Community Memorial Hospital (Toms River, N.J.), East Carolina Medical Services System (Washington, N.C.), Easter Seal Society of N.J., Honolulu Medical Group, and the N.J. Hispanic Task Force on Child Abuse and Neglect, 1980 Sep–1981 Jan (1 of 2) (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes tax exemptions. Contains Community Memorial Hospital (Toms River, N.J.), East Carolina Medical Services System (Washington, N.C.), Easter Seal Society of N.J., Honolulu Medical Group, and the N.J. Hispanic Task Force on Child Abuse and Neglect, 1980 Sep–1981 Jan (2 of 2) (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Monmouth County Office of the Handicapped: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1980 Dec–1981 Jan (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains South Branch Watershed Association, Raritan First Aid Squad, and International Youth Organization (Newark, N.J.), 1981 Feb–1981 Aug (1 of 2) (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains South Branch Watershed Association, Raritan First Aid Squad, and International Youth Organization (Newark, N.J.), 1981 Feb–1981 Aug (2 of 2) (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Y.M.C.A. of Eastern Union County and Meadows Foundation (Somerset, N.J.), 1981 Jun–1982 Feb (1 of 2) (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemptions. Contains Y.M.C.A. of Eastern Union County and Meadows Foundation (Somerset, N.J.), 1981 Jun–1982 Feb (2 of 2) (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Hillsborough Volunteer Fire Company No. 1 – Fire truck: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1981 Sep–Nov (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1982 Jan–Apr (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1982 Apr–Oct (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings, 1982 Oct–Dec (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files. Includes clippings and tax exemption, 1982 Nov–Dec (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Doris Duke Personal Fund A-C: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings and Animal Medical Center report on bovine leukemia at Duke Farms, 1957-1975 (1 of 2) (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Doris Duke Personal Fund A-C: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings and Animal Medical Center report on bovine leukemia at Duke Farms, 1957-1975 (2 of 2) (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Doris Duke Personal Fund D-N: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings and photographs, 1959-1973 (1 of 2) (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Doris Duke Personal Fund D-N: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings and photographs, 1959-1973 (2 of 2) (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Doris Duke Personal Fund O-W: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings and photographs, 1959-1971 (1 of 2) (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Doris Duke Personal Fund O-W: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings and photographs, 1959-1971 (2 of 2) (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Donations - Negro Colleges: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings, 1961-1971 (1 of 2) (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Donations - Negro Colleges: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings, 1961-1971 (2 of 2) (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Foundation Correspondence: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings, photograph, and correspondence with Independent Aid, Inc., 1948-1968 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Foundation Correspondence: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings, 1969-1972 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Foundation Correspondence: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings, 1972-1974 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Foundation Correspondence: May E. McFarland Files. Includes clippings, 1975 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Turner, S.W.H.: Donations, Closed Files. Includes correspondence regarding James B. Duke, 1941-1948 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Public Schools of Prince Edward County, Maryland. Request for funding to build schools for African American students who are not attending school due to segregation, circa 1950s (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from J.B. Rhine, Duke University, Parapsychology Laboratory, to Doris Duke regarding studes being conducted at Duke, 1957 Dec 9 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Presbyterian Hospital at Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center. A brief report, 1958 Apr 24 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Memoranda from multiple sources requesting aid for charities, 1958 Apr (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - American Farm School, Correspondence and photograph thanking Doris Duke for her donation to the school, 1958 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Two books given to Doris Duke by the Department of AA at Duke University. Possibly given as the result of donation made by Doris Duke, circa 1960s (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation general correspondence, 1964 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation - charitable deductions and donations, 1964-1967 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Donation Requests: Miscellaneous Donation Files, 1966, 1980-1987, 1991 (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Donations to Somerset Valley YMCA and Boys Harbor, 1967 (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Doris Duke Foundation general correspondence, 1980 (Box 103, Folder 14)
  - Gray Panthers donation request, circa 1980s (Box 103, Folder 15)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company Hawaii Proposal, 1990-1991 (Box 103, Folder 16)
  - Happiness is Camping, for children with cancer. Memoranda requesting funding, 1992 Apr-May (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Boys Clubsand Girls Clubs of Newport County, Inc. Request for a donation, 1992 Jul 7 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - WBGO, Jazz 88. Memorandum requesting a $25,000 grant. 1992 Jul (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding donations made by/requested from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1993 Nov (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - The Teleios Foundation, correspondence and printed materials sent to DDF requesting funding to aid Russian widows and orphans, 1993 Nov (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to recipients of donations from the Doris Duke Foundation, 1993 Dec 15 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Tax records for a loan to the Martha Graham School of Contemporary Dance, 1993-1999 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Requests made to the DDF for funding from the Virginia Beach SPCA, the Versailles Foundation, Inc., and Works, 1995-1996 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Invoice and proposal from Musication, 2009 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Brochure for the Constructive Research Foundation, undated (Box 104, Folder 10)